<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R and Python: A Beautiful Combination</title>
      <link>/blog/r-and-python-a-beautiful-combination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/r-and-python-a-beautiful-combination/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody. Today I will be doing a short demonstration on how R and Python can be used simultaneously in an R Markdown file. This will be done using the Reticulate package in R. Let’s load in the Reticulate and Tidyverse packages in R.
library(reticulate)library(tidyverse)## -- Attaching packages -------------------------------------------------------------- tidyverse 1.3.0 --## v ggplot2 3.3.0 v purrr 0.3.4## v tibble 3.0.1 v dplyr 0.8.5## v tidyr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 (Modeling, Testing, and Predicting)</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>#Introduction:
I am using the same datasets from Project 1. These datasets contain NFL player statistics from the 2019 regular season, as retrieved from Pro-Football-Reference. One dataset contains all rushing stats for applicable players and the other contains all receiving stats for applicable players. For the purposes of this project, these two datasets will be full joined together. We will also only be including skill position players (running back (RB), wide receiver (WR), and tight end (TE)) for this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1 (Exploratory Data Analysis)</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>#Introduction:
The two datasets I have chosen are NFL player statistics from the 2019 regular season, as retrieved from Pro-Football-Reference. The first dataset contains rushing stats for all applicable players (variables like rushing attempts, rushing yards, rushing touchdowns, etc.), and the second dataset contains receiving stats for all applicable players (variables like catches, receiving yards, receiving touchdowns, etc.). It is important to note that this list does not exclude quarterbacks, but it does exclude passing stats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>